# Mitru Carmen

Address: Str Nicolina nr 66, Bl 985B, Ap 1 – Iasi, Iasi RO Birthdate: 26 April 1997

Email: <a href="mailto:carmen.mitru@gmail.com">carmen.mitru@gmail.com</a> Mobile: +40748877595



# About Me

I started to learn computer science since I was a 13 years old. Until now I managed to learn (by myself) several computer technologies and programming languages. What makes me go further and learn more is an inner desire to create application, that can truly change the way we live.

#### Personal Skills

- Enthusiastic
- Competitive
- Open-mindedness

# Experience

### Web Developer

2014 - Present

#### **IT Trainer - Varilogic**

2015 - Present

As a trainer I teach students the basics of web development (HTML,CSS,Javascript)

#### **Achievements**

- 2015 Won 2<sup>nd</sup> Prize at a <u>Hackathon</u> held by Colegiul National "Emil Racovita", where I developed a responsive website, used to manage the schedule and calendars.
- **2015** Won 2<sup>nd</sup> Prize at <u>FII Practic Hackathon</u> with an web app that helps the new students to get used to the town.
- 2015 Participation at IT Marathon Hackathon
- **2015** Participation at IP Workshop Summer School ,where I developed an online shop using Angular Js and Firebase.
- **19 March, 2016** Won 3<sup>Rd</sup> at International Contest MobilPro at section Mobile Apps. I build a mobile app called StudentHelp, that helps new students who move in the new city to study .For this I used Ionic framework, AngularJs, Cordova, Firebase.
- 17 April, 2016 Won 2<sup>nd</sup> Prize at FII Pratic Hackathon
- **8 May, 2016** Won 3<sup>Rd</sup> Prize ar FII Code Contest at section web. I have developed with Dan Diaconu a platform called TimeLocker that helps students to manage their time in a better way.

  .https://github.com/carmen97/timelocker

- **14 May, 2016** Won 3<sup>Rd</sup> Prize in IT Marathon Web Section. I have developed a platform called DocumentShare that helps users to manage their documents.
- November 2016 February 2017 Student at Recurse Center, New York Recurse Center is a 3 months self-directed retreat for programmers in New York City.

Self study Javascript, Python and R. Focused on learning and implementing design patterns, algorithms, data structures, machine learning and idiomatic best practices for JS and Python.

- **22 March 2017** Participation in HackITAII held in Bucharest.The application created for this contest helped the restaurant to manage thei order. <a href="https://github.com/carmenmitru/HackItaII">https://github.com/carmenmitru/HackItaII</a>
- **1 April 2017** Won 2<sup>nd</sup> Prize at FIIPractic Hackton where I developed an online management platform for by studens and teachers. https://github.com/carmenmitru/OneStudentApp
- 27-28 April Participant Craft Conference, Budapest
- May 2016 July 2016 Participant Google CodeU EMEA

Working on algorithms and data structures coding problems using Java and was continuously receiving constructive feedback from appointed Google Software Engineers.

#### Education

### National College "Emil Racovita" - High School

2011 - 2015

I graduated high school on a computer science intensive class and I spend most of the time by participating in contests and taking extracurricular courses.

#### Faculty of Automatic Control and Computer Engineering Iasi

2015 - Present

# **Online Courses**

2013-2015

- <u>Database Design and Programming with SQL</u>
- <u>Fundamentals of Java Programming</u>
- <u>CISCO IT Essentials</u>

# Languages

### **English (Cambridge Certification)**

Speaking: B2Writing: B2Listening: B2Reading: B2

#### German (TestDAF Certification)

Speaking: B2Writing: B2Listening: B2

	Reading : B2
Programing skills	Web Development : HTML,CSS,JS( Angular2, Node Js) C++/Java